Raja Umer Saghir

Software Engineer



PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

As a Software Engineer with few years of experience in the IT field, my specialisation lies in full-stack web development, particularly in TypeScript, React, Next, Node, Git, Cloud, and related technologies. I am adept at solving complex problems and excel as a collaborative team player, backed by strong social and communication skills. My technical expertise spans responsive UI development, API development and integration, optimisation, CI/CD, unit testing. Proficiency in DevOps and agile practices is another facet of my skill set.



+46 767 464646



Malmo



umer.saghir@live.com



Swedish (EU)

COMPETENCES

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

TypeScript | JavaScript | HTML | CSS Java | Dart | Python | SQL | NoSQL

FRAMEWORKS & LIBRARIES

React | NEXT | Redux | Spring | Node Express | Bootstrap | Flutter | SASS SCSS | LESS | Tailwind | Material UI TOOLS

VS Code | NPM | Yarn | Git | GitLab GitHub Action | JEST | Firebase | GCP AWS | Docker | Slack | Jira | Figma | XD | Webpack | Heroku | Lucidchart

DATABASES

MySQL | PostgreSQL | MongoDB

OTHER SKILLS

Team work | Problem solving | UX/UI Agile | Scrum | Kanban | Analytical Communication | Math | Wordpress Shopify | Unit Testing | A/B Testing

LANGUAGES

- English (advanced)
- Swedish (intermediate)

REFERENCES

Will be provided when required.

WORK EXPERIENCE

FREELANCER, DEVELOPER

TeCodea (UpWork), 11/2022 - Continue

- Developed & testing of React, Next, SSR, CSR, SSG responsive apps.
- Implementing Hooks, Context API & Redux to manage app states.
- Implementing authentication, JWT, OAuth, Google & Firebase.
- Integration with FireStore & Cloud Bucket for image storage.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

PaperTale Technology AB, Malmo | 2/2021 - 9/2022

- Developing, testing & deploying React & Node web applications.
- Unit & A/B testing for performance & compatibility across devices.
- Developed Express API & deployed at Google Cloud VM instances.
- Version-control Git, GitHub, CICD pipeline, DevOps, Scrum & Agile.
- Collaboration with UI/UX designers, backend developers & Testers.
- Code reviews & feedback to peers to maintain code quality.

ENGINEER. CONSULTANT

Outso AB, Malmo | 6/2014 - 10/2019

- Developing & product listing at CMS websites & Shopify stores.
- Provided technical support, troubleshooting for web applications.
- Browser testing, troubleshooting & debugging of web apps.

EDUCATION

SYSTEM & WEB DEVELOPMENT COURSE

KTH & Novare Potential, Lund | 2/2020 - 05/2020

Java, SpringBoot, Data-structure, Algorithms, OOP, Software Engineering, Problem Solving, Unit Testing, Team-Work, individual, group project.

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT COURSE

Foo Coding, Malmo | 12/2018 - 05/2019

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Responsive design, React, Context API, Software development, Node, Express, Git, GitHub, Database, SQL, HTTP, AJAX.

MSC ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING

BTH, Karlskrona | 2010 - 2013

MORE INFORMATION





